Vincent B. Bergeron Beng GMICE

Nationality: Canadian

Mobile No. +44 7588 441407

Email: vincentbergeron33@gmail.com

TEMPRARY WORKS COORDINATOR

PROFILE

I am a highly motivated Civil Engineer with over seven years of experience in construction and military field as an assistant project manager and an officer of the Canadian Armed Forces. Currently working for multi-international contracting company as a Temporary Works Coordinator in the United Kingdom on the major project HS2. My section of work is the connection to the main train station in the most crowded area of Birmingham which bring challenges of multiply stakeholders coordination. My background as military officer strengthened the ability to communicate with a diverse team, build good relationships and able to manage and motivate everyone. During my works for the main contractor I developed strong interpersonal and communication skills with an ability to influence and engage stakeholders within the organisation and externally.

I adapt well to new situations in fast-paced work environment and possess strong analytical, problem solving and mathematical abilities.

SKILLS, KNOWLEDGE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- ✓ Full driving licence
- ✓ Advanced Skills in AutoCAD and Revit
- ✓ Surveying using GPS and Total Station
- ✓ Use of MathCAD, Matlab, Mapple, ARCGIS
- ✓ Languages spoken: French, English, Polish
- ✓ Ability to plan and follow the project specifications
- ✓ Quality Management

- ✓ Strong understanding importance of health and safety on construction sites
- ✓ Civil and utilities engineering
- ✓ Ease of working under high pressure
- ✓ Efficient problem solver
- ✓ Strong leadership skills and team player
- ✓ Strong interpersonal and communication skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Temporary Works Coordinator

Vinci UK

November 2020 – Now Birmingham, UK

- Support all design & construction activities within structures, roads and creating of fully operatives temporary working compounds;
- o Programme and plan the temporary works to govern the priorities for temporary works designs;
- Guidance and lead the onsite control all Temporary Works activities within the given section of the project:
- o Review of method statement and work plans and other construction documents;
- Monitoring the TW design of the supply chain, report on progress, provide information and ensure coordination between all parties;
- o Ensure the residual risks identified by the permanent and temporary works designer are addresses in accordance with CDM2015 and ensure that a CDM Design Risk Register is maintained;
- o Development of accurate design briefs in consultation with site and design teams;
- Creation and maintenance of schedules to track and control schemes temporary works;
- Identify competent designers, suppliers & operatives for installation of each type of temporary works,
 and to co-ordinate & supervise their work;
- o Liaison with Technical Approval Authority and external approval bodies such as Highways Authorities,
- Network Rail, Statutory Undertakers;
- Support the Contractor Engineering Manager (CEM) for the issue of Form C, IDC, IDR and DRNs to Network Rail;
- o Support the CEM during Meeting with Network Rail;
- Develop and issue G17 process for Cadent approval;
- Ensure business processes and systems for Temporary Works are implemented;

Temporary Works Coordinator

Skanska UK

March 2019 – July 2020 London, United Kingdom

- O Supervision of temporary and permanent works from inceptions to completion;
- o Performing daily site inspections for all civil works;
- o Preparing and review the design calculations, drawings and project specifications;
- o Design and detailing of system formwork, falsework and access equipment;
- o Create cost estimates and needed technical documentations;
- o Prepare and review design calculations, method statements and risk assessments;
- o Manage and coordinate with the main stakeholder Network Rail;
- o Preparing KPI, progress reports and assist in data analysis from subcontractors works.

Combat Engineer Officer

April 2016 – December 2018

Quebec, CANADA

Canadian Armed Forces (Militia)

- o Constructing habitable military camps;
- o Installing temporary drainage for the campsites:
- o Breaching minefields and disposing explosives;
- Using explosives to destroy a road or a bridge;
- o Constructing a bridge and building a combat road;
- Overlooking trench support for water main installation;
- Witnessing welding procedures for all pipe works;
- o Develop leadership skills in extreme circumstances.

Project Engineer

Hamel Construction

July 2015 – April 2016 Quebec, CANADA

Wind Turbine

- o Plan of all works of the assembly of the wind turbine;
- O Structural inspection of the foundation and the tower;
- Electrical & mechanical connection within the structure;
- o Manage, control and supervise construction quality, health and safety on site;
- o Create monitoring system for the inventory of the equipment on site;
- o Undertaken logistics of the transport within the construction site.

Highway 73 North

- o Design plans for traffic management;
- Responsible for the inventory and installation of road signs;
- o Managing the existing drainage system;
- o Perform cost estimates, quantity take-off and prepare detailed Bill of Quantities for the project;
- o Perform structural design and analyses of bridge repair method.

Other responsibilities

- o Manage and coordinate plans and specifications for the client's submission;
- o Liaise with subcontractors and other stakeholders;
- Identify of all requirements during estimation and bidding process to obtain the optimum cost and quality.

Quality Assurance Engineer, Internship

May 2014 – August 2014 Quebec, CANADA

Enercon CA

Wind Turbine St-Philemon

- Overseeing quality control and health and safety matters on site;
- o Monitor the quality of the foundation during construction phase;
- o Production of the technical documentation on the quality of foundations;
- o Maintain and control project quality metrics during concrete casting and repairs.

Quality Assurance Engineer, Internship

Enercon CA

May 2013 – August 2013 Quebec, CANADA

Wind Turbine St-Ferdinand

- o Perform technical support during the construction of the wind turbine;
- o Conduct an inventory of the machinery of the wind turbine project;
- Control the programme of the wind turbine project;
- o Production of the technical documentation on the development of a wind turbine project.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

EDUCATION

- o Bachelor degree in Civil Engineering at the University Laval in Quebec, Canada, 2011 2015.
- o Graduate member of ICE-Institution of Civil Engineers

COMPENTENCES

- o Temporary Works below and above ground design IstructE
- o Temporary Works Coordinator -CITB accredited
- o Health and Safety on construction site CITB
- o SMSTS Sate Management Safety Training Scheme CITB
- o Quality management ISO
- o Ground investigation, Geotechnical Data & Earthworks ICE
- o SEATS Site Environmental Awareness & Deep Green training